# Josef 'Jay' Barbanel

Los Angeles, 917.510.3408, jbarbanel531@gmail.com

### PROFILE

Front-End Developer with an understanding of back-end functionalities. Combining a ten year career representing photographers and directors, with the love of visual arts and understanding of code, brings a great asset to a company looking for an entry level developer. Ability and confidently leading teams, working in fast paced environments and a desire to achieve a common goal while fully immersing into the company's culture and job role.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Apr 2022 — Present

## Frontend Developer, Hack for LA

- Responsible for adding new features to the HFLA website along with refactoring legacy code.
- Coordinating across multiple disciplines (designers, product managers, developers) while operating with current JavaScript libraries and frameworks.
- Implementing markdown and Liquid to certain Jekyll pages using Docker Compose.
- Working in an Agile software development environment.

#### Mar 2022 — Present

## Front End Developer | Creative Direction, The Grace Network

Los Angeles, CA

View Website: gracenetworkchi.org

Responsible for all front-end design and website maintenance. Working closely with the Founder & Board Member responsible for Technology throughout the organization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Nov 2021 — Feb 2022

## **UCLA Extension Bootcamp**

Coding and Software Engineering Bootcamp

Sep 2004 — May 2011

Photography & Digital Imagery, Ringling College of Art and Design

# PROJECTS

### The Commissioner App

Los Angeles, CA

**Role:** Full front-end design, creative direction, back-end floater, main presentation. **GitHub**: <a href="mailto:github.com/JayBarbanel/Commissioner">github.com/JayBarbanel/Commissioner</a> | **Deployed:** <a href="mailto:peaceful-cliffs-88132.herokuapp.com/">peaceful-cliffs-88132.herokuapp.com/</a> I This MVP app was built to help basketball fans all over the world stay up to date with their favorite NBA teams. By using the NBAAPI, users are able to create a profile, login and select their favorite team. Once they select their team, real time statistics show up on a new page. Users may also update their favorite team in order to see what's going on across the league. The app was built in React.JS, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

### Call of Duty Warzone Weapon Reviewer

Los Angeles, CA

Role: Full front-end design, creative direction, main presentation. **GitHub**:github.com/JayBarbanel/CoD-Weapons-Reviewer | **Deployed**: nameless-plain

github.com/JayBarbanel/CoD-Weapons-Reviewer | **Deployed**: nameless-plains-70878.herokuapp.com/login | This MVP app was built for Warzone fans everywhere. Users create an account, login and are brought to a page where they can select which type of weapon they would like to review. From there, they are brought to a selection of different guns where they can add their name and their review. There is a page that saves their review and when it was created. This app was built using HTML, CSS, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Google Fonts and JavaScript.

## PAST WORK EXPERIENCE (2011-2021)

# Early Morning Riot | Creative Consultant

Los Angeles, CA

Advised Photographers & Directors with their projects, portfolios, raised rates and budgets.

### TACK Artist Group | Agent

Los Angeles, CA

Represented a roster of 13 top Directors and Photographers.